# MICHAEL FARES

703-244-0370 | mjfares@gmail.com

https://github.com/Michael-Fares https://michaelfares.netlify.app https://michael-fares.medium.com

## FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER | EDUCATOR

I'm a JavaScript developer with a versatile skill set in frontend / full stack technologies and best practices. I'm also an award winning educator with 10 years of university teaching experience. My goal is to use my skills to build outstanding digital learning platforms, making education equitable for 21st century learners everywhere.

### **Core Competencies**

Frontend Development • Backend Development • Unit Testing • Agile Workflow • Relational Databases • SEO • Continuous Integration and Deployment • Web Accessibility • Curriculum Design • Educational Technology • Teaching/Higher Education • Research/Data Analysis • Fluent in Arabic

### **Technical Skills**

HTML • CSS • Bootstrap • JavaScript • React • Redux • MaterialUI • Chart.js • Recharts.js • Node • NPM • Express • REST API • Git • Github • Google Cloud (GCP) • Heroku • Netlify • MySQL • AWS • ESLint

## **EXPERIENCE**

Zollege, Austin, TX

### **Software Developer**

I work closely with a team of fellow developers to plan, design, build and integrate new full stack web applications and features into various digital learning platforms.

- Whiteboard and implement robust frontend user interfaces to deliver educational content to students
- Identify and collaboratively solve problems related to frontend-backend integration

University of Houston, Houston, TX

Aug 2012 - Present

Jan 2022 - Present

#### **Professor of Arabic**

I teach Arabic as a second language to hundreds of college students from many backgrounds, and work on multiple administrative teams to deliver extracurricular offerings including community internships, study abroad, and public cultural events.

- Design, implement, and maintain original Arabic language curriculum content for all levels
- Multiple published articles and public talks on Arabic language, culture, translation and best teaching practices.
- Faculty Teaching Excellence Award, 2020
- Outstanding Mentorship Award, 2020

Greenhill School, Dallas, TX

Aug 2009 - June 2010

#### Middle School Teacher

- Created and taught original lesson plans for 5th graders in all subjects.
- Supervised students during after school programs and planned activities to ensure their learning and fun.
- Communicated regularly with parents about students' progress and learning needs...

## **EDUCATION**

Austin Coding Academy Bootcamp

Full Stack Web Development | December 2021

University of Texas at Austin

MA, Arabic Language | May 2012